cloudmagic.com 2017-05-12

# Newton for iPhone, iPad, Android & Mac | Privacy Policy

##### Introduction

This Policy describes what information we collect when you use our service and how we use this information collected. We are not in the business of loaning, renting or selling information to others. We only use the information collected to better the service offered to you. 

##### Your privacy is important to us

CloudMagic, Inc. is committed to protect your privacy. Through the Newton website and mobile applications, we collect two types of user information: General Statistical Information and Personal Identifying Information. 

##### Collection, use and disclosure of General Statistical Information

When you visit our website and use our applications we gather usage statistics. This information is referred to throughout this Policy as "General Statistical Information". We use and store this data only on a collective basis, in summary form, rather than on an individual basis. This data helps us to determine how and the extent to which certain parts of our website and applications are used. The stored General Statistical Information does not contain any Personal Identifying Information about you or any of our other users. 

##### Collection and use of Personal Identifying Information

In addition to collecting General Statistical Information, we may ask you to provide us with certain personal information. Information that can reasonably be used to identify you is referred to in this Policy as "Personal Identifying Information". The following describes each aspect of Personal Identifying Information: 

  1. Account info

The first email address you add to Newton app becomes the username for your Newton account. If you were to use Newton app in a different mobile device, you can log in using Newton account and all your email accounts will be available instantly. We might also use that email address to reach out to you periodically. 

  2. Account authentication/passwords and data

Accounts are added to Newton through OAuth authentication (where possible). OAuth is a secure mechanism which gives us access to your data without letting us know your password.

Where OAuth is not supported, we keep your account username and password in our secure servers. 

We then use the authorization provided to download your emails on the cloud and push to your devices. We use AWS servers to store your data: emails and authorization. [Here is an overview of AWS’ security policies](http://aws.amazon.com/security/). Apart from that we take a number of security measures to ensure that your data is never read by anyone else.

We also ensure that all transmission is secure using HTTPS so that no one else can access your data. 

  3. Scope of download

Emails: Newton uses the cloud to download and push emails to your device. To get you started Newton downloads and pushes only recent emails — emails sent or received in the last 14 days for mobile and 60 days for Mac — to your device. The email attachments are not downloaded on the cloud and are served from the respective services in real-time. 

Newton Connected Apps: Newton surfaces contextual Cards that help you get your work done. Newton pulls the data from respective tools in real-time and does not download it on the cloud in advance.

  4. Sender profile

We obtain and store information from our third-party partners about people that e-mail you. We will use this information to improve the service by showing you contextual cards about the senders. 

  5. Read Receipts

Read Receipts allows you to see the read/unread status of your sent e-mails without any notification to the recipient. We collect and track information about your sent email in order for you to use this feature. 

  6. Usage

Your data is used solely to enable you do your emailing and get your work done with Newton Connected Apps. We don’t loan, rent or sell your data. 

  7. Our policy towards children

CloudMagic does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have inadvertently collected personally identifiable information such as email address or name from children under the age of 13, we will promptly delete it. Parents and guardians can contact us on [hello@newtonhq.com](mailto:hello@newtonhq.com) if they are aware that their child has provided us with personal information without their consent. 

  8. Support queries

The support queries you write to us about might contain personal information. We use this information solely to help you resolve the issues reported and improve the product quality. 

##### Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is sent from a web server to your browser and stored on your computer. We use persistent session cookies which ensure that you don't have to login each time you visit. Newton never stores your information that we consider personal or private in a cookie. In addition to our own cookies, we make use of third-party services like Google Analytics to track usage and volume statistics to help us analyse how the service is used. Because Newton is entirely personalized, your browser must accept cookies for us to provide our services to you.

##### Deletion of account authentication/passwords and data

In the event you delete your data from Newton, or revoke access to your data, or delete your Newton account, your entire index as well as your authentication/password information is completely and permanently deleted from our servers, and we therefore do not have access to any of your data anymore.

##### Disclosure of Personal Identifying Information

We will only disclose your Personal Identifying Information to third parties if we are required to do so by law, or if we believe that such action is necessary to comply with legal processes such as a search warrant, subpoena, or court order. 

We never loan, rent or sell your Personal Identifying Information to others. 

If CloudMagic and / or Newton should have its assets sold to or merged with another entity, user information collected through the service may be among the items sold or transferred. The user will have the rights to delete his/her data.

##### Third-party websites

The CloudMagic website may contain links to third-party websites over which we have no control or responsibility regarding content, privacy policies, or practices. We suggest that you review the Privacy Policy applicable to any third party site that you visit. This Privacy Policy applies only to our own website at https://cloudmagic.com.

##### Changes to the CloudMagic Privacy Policy

CloudMagic reserves the right to change, modify, add or remove portions of the Privacy Policy in its sole discretion at any time and without prior notice. We will indicate the last update date of each update at the bottom of this page. Please check the Privacy Policy periodically for any modifications. If you have any comments on this Privacy Policy please email us at [hello@newtonhq.com](mailto:hello@newtonhq.com) or write to us at: 

CloudMagic, Inc.  
501 Forest Avenue, Suite 209  
Palo Alto, CA 94301

Last updated: September 14, 2016
